Guide to the Vincent Cianni Photographs, 1983-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Vincent Cianni photographs 1983-2004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cianni, Vincent
21.0 linear feet Extent: 604 Items
Vincent Cianni is a documentary photographer based in Newburgh, New York. Arranged in the following series: the Berlin Series features photographs of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall, and the reunification of Germany in 1990. The Poughkeepsie Mall Series and the Providence House Men's Shelter Series both document urban culture and decay in the 1980s. The Weddings Series includes Cianni's MFA project, Wedding Rituals, along with other photographs from weddings (including some transgender weddings) during the mid-1980s. Finally, the Brooklyn Series features images from Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side, which depict Hispanic American youth and roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, during the mid-1990s. Collection also includes digital files and media related to Cianni's published works.
RL.00238
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research and educational, non-commercial use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Some digital media need reformatting before content can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Vincent Cianni Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2008, 2009, and 2010.
Biographical Note
Vincent Cianni is a documentary photographer based in Newburgh, New York.
Collection Overview
Accession (2007-0072) houses a series of 224 black and white photographic prints depicting roller blade and street culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, taken by Cianni during the 1990s and into 2001. Fifteen of the prints appear in Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side (2001); and 68 prints are unpublished. Photographs are captioned and signed on the back. Also included are photographs of urban life in the Bronx, NY; and from the baby shower (Queens, NY) and wedding (Fairborn, OH) of a young couple who appear in other images from this series. Finally, the series houses the maquette for Cianni's book (version 1, 2000), and the printer's dummy (versions 2-3, 2001-2004).
Accession (2007-0200) contains 65 black and white, gelatin silver prints and photographic collages of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall and the reunification of Berlin, 1990. Prints range from 8x10 to 16x24 and are captioned and signed on back by the photographer.
Accession (2008-0048) contains prints from the Poughkeepsie Mall Series (Poughkeepsie, NY, 1980s) and the Providence House Men's Shelter Series (Newburgh, NY, 1983). Forty-four black and white photographic prints: one 5 5/8 x 8 ½; one 5 7/8 x9; and forty-two 11x14 prints. Poughkeepsie Mall series: twenty-two 11x14 prints, 1980s. Images depict youth culture, African American culture, and urban decay.
Accession (2008-0300) contains 184 prints of weddings, including some transexual weddings, taken by Cianni during the 1980s. This series includes Cianni's MFA project, Wedding Rituals, a group of twenty-four 20x24 prints and one 16x20 print. Photographs in this series are in both color and black and white; many are captioned and signed on the back by the photographer.
Accession (2008-0303) contains an additional 23 8x10 duotone and gelatin silver prints from Cianni's book We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side. These prints include portraits and other images of Hispanic American youth roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York during the mid-1990s.
Accession (2009-0243) houses forty-two black and white photographs of Muay Thai style of kickboxing competition in Siem Reap, Cambodia, 2004: thirty-six 8x10 prints and six 16x20 prints.
Finally, Accession (2010-0187) includes forty-seven 8x10 black and white gelatin silver prints from the We Skate Hardcore series. The prints are signed on verso and date 1995-2003, with bulk dates 1995-1997.
In addition, the collection contains digital video, stills, and image scans created by Vincent Cianni, all relating to his work We Skate Hardcore. Originals are closed to use. Most files have been mounted to the library server; for access to them, please contact the reference archivist.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Subject Headings
African Americans -- United States -- Social conditions; Berlin Wall, Berlin, Germany, 1961-1989 -- Pictorial works; Berlin (Germany)--History -- 1945-1990 -- Pictorial works; Bronx (New York, N.Y.)--Pictorial works; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Pictorial works; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Social conditions; Cianni, Vincent; Cities and towns -- United States; Documentary photography -- United States; Duke University. Archive of Documentary Arts; Germany (East)--Pictorial works; Hispanic Americans -- New York (State).; In-line skating -- New York (City).; Kickboxing -- Cambodia; Martial arts -- Cambodia; Newburgh (N.Y.)--Pictorial works; New York State -- Pictorial works; New York State -- Social conditions; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--Pictorial works; Transgender people -- United States; Queens (New York, N.Y.)--Pictorial works; Weddings -- Pictorial works; Youth -- United States -- Social conditions; Photographs; Digital audio tapes; Machine readable records; Gelatin silver prints; CD-Rs; DVDs
Related Material
Duke University also has a copy of Vincent Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side. Please refer to the library catalog for more information.
Contents of Collection
- Berlin, 1990, (4 boxes)
  Accession (2007-0200) contains 65 gelatin silver prints and photographic collages of East Berlin, the destruction of the Berlin Wall, and the reunification of Berlin, 1990. Print range in size from 8x10 to 16x24 and are captioned and signed on back by photographer.
  - Berlin prints (Box 1-4)
- Poughkeepsie Mall, 1980s, and Providence House Men's Shelter, 1983, (2 boxes)
  Accession (2008-0048) contains prints from the Poughkeepsie Mall series (Poughkeepsie, NY, 1980s) and the Providence House Men's Shelter (Newburgh, NY, 1983). There are 44 black and white photographic prints: one 5 5/8 x 8 ½; one 5 7/8 x 9; and forty-two 11x14 prints. The Poughkeepsie Mall series contains twenty-two 11x14 prints shot in the 1980s. Images depict American youth culture, African American culture, and urban decay.
  - Poughkeepsie Mall and Providence House prints (Box 5-6)
- Weddings, 1980s, (5 boxes)
  Accession (2008-0300) contains 184 prints of weddings, including some transexual weddings, taken by Cianni during the 1980s. This series includes Cianni's MFA project, Wedding Rituals, a group of twenty-four 20x24 prints and one 16x20 print. Photographs in this series are in both color and black and white; many are captioned and signed on the back by the photographer.
  - Wedding Rituals MFA project:, (24 20x24 black and white photographs, 1 16x20 black and white photograph) (Box 7)
  - Transexual weddings:, 16 (16x20) black and white photographs (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous:, 11 (16x20) black and white photographs
  - Tom and Alison's wedding, Rockville Center, New York:, 18 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 9)
  - Ring bearers at Pat Devaney's wedding, Cape May, New Jersey, 1983:, 3 (8x10) black and white photographs
  - Knowles/Mortimer wedding, Canadaigua, New York:, 22 (8x10) black and white photographs
  - Kaplan/Kreiger wedding, New York City, 1989:, 16 (8x10) black and white photographs (Box 10)
  - Kaplan/Kreiger wedding snapshots:, 12 (3x5) color photographs
  - Kershaw wedding, Clinton Corners, New York, 1987:, 5 (5x7) black and white photographs
  - Laura and Edmund's wedding, West Orange, New Jersey, 1991:, 7 (5x7) black and white photographs
  - Taylor/Kahene wedding, Cape May, New Jersey, 1986:, 5 (5x7) black and white photographs, 5 (3x5) color photographs
  - Weddings:, 38 (11x14) black and white photographs, 1 (6.75x14.5) black and white photograph (Box 11)
- Brooklyn, 1990s-2004, (7 boxes)
  Accession (2007-0072) houses a series of 224 black and white photographic prints depicting Hispanic American youth roller blade and street culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, shot by Cianni during the 1990s and into 2001. Many of the prints appear in Cianni's book, We Skate Hardcore: Photographs from Brooklyn's South Side (2001), and a number of prints are unpublished. Photographs are captioned and signed on the back. Also included are photographs of urban life in the Bronx, NY; and from the baby shower in Queens, NY, and the wedding in Fairborn, Ohio of a young couple who appear in other images from this series. Finally, the series houses the maquette for Cianni's book (version 1, 2000), and the printer's dummy (versions 2-3, 2001-2004).
  Accession (2008-0303) contains twenty-three 8x10 duotone and gelatin silver prints from Cianni's book We Skate Hardcore, and includes portraits and other images of Hispanic American youth roller blade culture in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York, during the mid-1990s.
  Accession (2010-0187) includes forty-seven 8x10 black and white gelatin silver prints from the We Skate Hardcore series. The prints are signed on verso and date 1995-2003, with bulk dates 1995-1997.
  - Accession (2008-0303)
    - Brooklyn:, 23 (8x10) black and white prints (Box 12)
  - Accession (2007-0072)
    - Brooklyn:, 83 black and white (8x10) prints, published and unpublished (Box 13)
    - Brooklyn:, 37 black and white (11x14) published prints (Box 14)
    - Brooklyn:, 36 black and white (11x14) unpublished prints (Box 15)
    - Brooklyn:, 68 black and white (11x14) unpublished prints (Box 16)
    - Brooklyn: Maquette, version 1 (Box 17)
    - Brooklyn: Printer's dummy, version 2-3 (Box 18)
  - Accession (2010-0187)
    - Brooklyn:, 47 black and white (8x10) prints, signed on verso (Box 21)
- Cambodian Boxers Series, 2004, (2 boxes)
  Accession (2009-0243) contains 42 gelatin silver prints depicting the Muay Thai style of kickboxing competition in Siem Reap, Cambodia 2004. The prints are arranged in three groupings by the photographer: a sequence of 21 8x10 prints; a sequence of 15 8x10 prints; and six 16x20 prints.
  - 8x10 black and white prints (Box 19)
    - Muay Thai, Siem Reap, part 1, (21 black and white prints)
    - Muay Thai, Siem Reap, part 2, (15 black and white prints)
  - 16x20 prints, Muay Thai, Siem Reap, (6 black and white prints) (Box 20)
- Digital Material, 2001-2004 and undated, (1 folder)
  CD-Rs, Mini-DV (digital video), and digital audio discs containing video stills, scans, interviews, and a video created by Vincent Cianni, all relating to the We Skate Hardcore project. Some paper prints of images are included with the CDs. Most files of scans have been mounted to the library server.
  [Original recordings are closed to use. For access to digital materials, please contact Research Services staff.]
  - Digital media (9 CD-Rs, 1 Mini-DV - video, 3 mini-discs - audio) (Box 18)